Hello developers. Welcome back to our SQL tutorial series. So today we are going to explore the
powerful order class in the SQL, which allows us to sort our query result in the specific order.
So first of all, simply understand the definition for the SQL order by class.
So the order by class is to sort the result set of the SQL query. Based on the more column,
it is incredibly handy for organizing data the way we want it to act. So let's start with the
closer look with some example. Okay. So first of all, I can use the start with some example
of sorting in the ascending order. Okay. So just sorting the result based on the single column
in the ascending order. So first of all, we have to specify the select
this prompt and table name, first of all, employees. Okay. And next step here, I can use for
order by okay. So our DER order by class and this here type the last name. Okay. So we define
for the last name column. And here we can create this, the ascending column. So here,
this little trip or the request from the employee stable and the ordering
for the last column is ascending order. Okay. This query returns the employee sorted alphabetically
by the last name. So first of all, here, select this statement and for lexicute and you can see
here, define for the last name for the first, the employee or ID tree and then the last to the early
and juhan and the okay. So I hope you perfectly understand, it is called the ascending order.
So next step here, sorting in the descending order. Okay. So the order, also sort of data in the
descending order, which will reverse the ascending order. Okay. So now just do for here and here,
we can remove this, the last name and here inside for the age column. Okay. And then I can define
the descending order. So define for the D, S, C. So you can understand. So just I can retrieve all the
records from the table and ordering the age column in the descending order. Okay. So now just I can select
and execute. And you can see here, your result and this query is written for your employees
sorted from the oldest to the young guest. Okay. So I hope you understand it and you can see
here, the age serial. Okay. So this is the age row. So I hope you perfectly understand it. So
this is complete for to this example. Next step here, create sorting by the multiple columns. Okay.
So now just type a news order by class allows us to sort the multiple columns, which can be used
for more complex sorting needs. Okay. So just go here. You can select for templates table
and use for here the order type the department. Okay. So just here, I can type it is called the
department. And first of all, I can remove the descending order and here I can inside
it is called the ascending order. And there was a comma and then there also insert for the ages
DSC descending order. Okay. So this example, we retrieve all the records from the table and ordering
them first by the department in descending order, then by the age of the descending order. Okay.
So now just select an execute. You can see here the result and in this query, just return
the employee sorted by the department for first. And we can see the department for the sorted
age from the oldest to the youngest. Okay. So first the 28 years old, then 29 is the youngest. Okay.
So 27 older and 30, the youngest and here you can see, serially maintained in this serial. Okay.
So now also it is done. And next step here is for the handling the null values. Okay.
In this order by class also allows us to control the placement of the null values in the sorted
variables. Okay. So now just check again. And first of all here, I can create this is the order by
for the department of the synchronous order and the ages, the synchronous and here also
nulls lost. Okay. So define for the nulls and here I can just type the last. Okay. And then
this semicolon and this example, retrieving or recruit from the employee stable and ordering
them by the department in the ascending order. And ages, descending order, additionally, this is
specified that where the null values for the age column should appear in the sorted ways of
okay. So now just check and verify an execute. You can see here, this is here incorrect syntax. Now
okay. So here we can completely incorrect. So here you can use the null and check. So you can see
here I created for the error mark. Okay. So you can hear handling the null values. Okay. So here I have
already created the example perfectly done and showed the output in the display. So I'm happy to
give the value of the order by clause in the SQL over there some practical example. Okay. So I hope
you find this tutorial helpful. So I hope you perfectly understand the SQL example and stay tuned
for more SQL tips and tricks. So thank you for watching and happy coding.